# Tan Yin Lin 陈颖宁

## WRITER / JOURNALIST

SINGAPORE (AVAILABLE FOR RELOCATION AND REMOTE WORK)

#### PROFILE —

- Journalism. Passion for understanding the world through journalism. Curious about current affairs and particularly interested in issues related to East Asia.
   Adaptable, resourceful, and adept at establishing contacts by building trust and relationships with others. A team player who thrives in high-pressure environments and delivers well-written copies under tight deadlines.
- Research. Research experience in academia and journalism. Engaged
  essential skills such as data analysis and interpretation, fact-checking,
  proof-reading, transcription, translation, and conducting interviews. Persistent
  and adaptable in the face of research obstacles. Committed to conducting
  rigorous research to produce honest reporting and thoughtful analysis.

EXPERIENCE ---

## RICE Media

Editorial Intern

Report and write features, op-eds, and commentaries with a focus on culture and current affairs. Pitch story ideas, craft angles for breaking news, and create branded content for clients. Collaborate with editors, designers, and producers to produce insightful articles. Full list of bylines at <a href="https://www.ricemedia.co/author/tan-yin-lin/">https://www.ricemedia.co/author/tan-yin-lin/</a>.

### Atlas Obscura, TripZilla, etc.

Freelance Writer

Pitch original story ideas to digital media publications. Handle the entire journalistic process, from crafting angles to sourcing for contacts, doing research and fieldwork, and taking photos. Full portfolio at <a href="https://tylanin.github.io/writing/">https://tylanin.github.io/writing/</a>.

# **National University of Singapore**

MAY 2018 - MAY 2020

NOV 2016 - PRESENT

MAY 2020 - JUL 2020

Research Assistant

Held multiple part-time positions with the Psychology and English Language Departments. Conducted research, facilitated experiments, and analysed data.

L'Oreal NOV 2015

Digital Media Intern

Drafted social media calendar for Garnier Singapore. Wrote product copies for L'Oreal's online store. Part of the English Language Elective Scholarship (ELES) programme.

#### EDUCATION -

## **National University of Singapore**

JUL 2016 - JUL 2020

B.A. Honours (1st Class) in English Language + University Scholars Programme Attained CAP of 4.59. Coursework in linguistics, philosophy, writing, statistics, and psychology. Member of Dance Blast! and D'Hoppers Dance Crew. Participated in my college's road relay, live music, and Pecha Kucha (storytelling, but snappy) clubs.

### http://tvlanin.github.io

+65 9783 9096 tylanin@gmail.com

#### PROJECTS ---

2020 · INTER.TXT, Writer/Editor 2020 · 134wpm, Writer/Editor 2019 · XDS Data Storytelling Competition, 4th Place

### SKILLS -

Writing · Reporting · Editing · Research · Data Interpretation · English-Mandarin Translation · Transcription · Interviewing · Photography · Web Design

#### LANGUAGES ---

Native: English, Mandarin Chinese Basic: Korean, Japanese, French Receptive: Hokkien, Teochew

# SOFTWARE -

HTML · CSS · Photoshop · Premiere Pro · Illustrator · Microsoft Suite · Audacity · Audition · ELAN · PRAAT

# AWARDS ----

2018 · USP Senior Honour Roll
2017 · Faculty of Arts and Sciences
Special Book Prize (Top Student)
2017 · USP Honour Roll
2015 · English Language Elective
Scholarship (ELES)